<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 10:11:39 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Use and remove seasonality in time series analysis?</title>
      <link>/blog/time_series_deseason/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jul 2021 10:11:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/time_series_deseason/</guid>
      <description>“A repeating pattern within each year is known as seasonal variation, although the term is applied more generally to repeating patterns within any fixed period” – Introductory Time Series with R
As the definition shown above, seasonality is another characteristic of time series datasets. It usually contains cycles that repeat over a specific time period. However, the repeating cycles may obscure the signal that we wish to model when conducting time series forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use and remove trends in time series analysis?</title>
      <link>/blog/time_series_detrend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 18:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/time_series_detrend/</guid>
      <description>Trend is one of the characteristics of time series data. In this article, we will talk about trends and how to remove them.
Trend is a continued increase or decrease in the series over time. There are different types of trends, such as deterministic trend, which are trends that are consistently increasing or decreasing. Another trend type that changes inconsistently(stochastic trends). Identifying trends in time series datasets can lead to faster modeling, simplification of the problems and improvement upon model performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is decomposition in time series analysis?</title>
      <link>/blog/time_series_decomposition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 18:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/time_series_decomposition/</guid>
      <description>Decomposition is primarily used in time series analysis. It involves thinking of a series in terms of level, trend, seasonality, and noise components. These four components are defined as follow:
🔎 Level: The average value in the series
🔎 Trend: The increasing or decreasing trend
🔎 Seasonality: The repeating cycle in terms of seasons
🔎 Noise: Random variation
Why it’s important to decompose? The time series decomposition helps with forecasting by breaking a time series down into different components – systematic and non-systematic components.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>discover hidden diseases topics with LDA</title>
      <link>/blog/lda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 22:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/lda/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Topic modeling for analyzing healthcare-related content has been used extensively. Latent Dirichlet Allocation(LDA) is one of the most famous topic modeling methods. LDA can help to discover hidden topics in document collections. In healthcare, it can be used for searching hidden disease topics.
For example, Prier et al.(2012) used LDA to identify several topics from health-related tweets, and found out that twitter users typically discussed strategies to quit smoking and recover from smoking addiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clinical Decision Support Systems(CDSS)</title>
      <link>/blog/healtcare_cdss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 22:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/healtcare_cdss/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Last time, we talked about data sources and coding system. Electronic Health Record system is where the patient&amp;rsquo;s records being stored. Different coding system(ICD-9, ICD-10, SNOWMED-CT, etc) are being used to ensure consistency and communication. This post will talk about Clinical Decision Support System(CDSS), a computer-based programs that analyzes data from EHR.
Clinical Decision Support System(CDSS) Clinical Decision Support System is used for assisting patient-related decision making process. It can effectively determine the optimal treatment, estimating clinical and financial outcomes of different treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>healthcare data sources</title>
      <link>/blog/healtcare_data_source/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 22:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/healtcare_data_source/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Healthcare analytics has gained more popularity in the recent years. Healthcare analytics includes but not limited to: biomedical image analysis, sensor data analysis, biomedical signal analysis, clinical text mining, clinical prediction models, Clinical Decision Support Systems(CDSS), fraud detection, etc.
This post will talk about healthcare data sources, coding system, and
1. Electronic Health Record (EHR) EHR, or electric health record is where patient&amp;rsquo;s medical histories are stored at. With EHR, patient&amp;rsquo;s medical records are easier to retrieved by health providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>association rule mining</title>
      <link>/blog/association_rule/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 21:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/association_rule/</guid>
      <description>Association rule mining Last time, we talked about healthcare analytics using predictive or descriptive methods. This post will talk about association rule mining, which aims to find co-occurrences of disease carried by a patient using the health care repository.
The research has proved that getting one disease can lead to one or more several disease. For example, a patient with diabetes is more likely to have other conditions, such as hypertension, and increase the risk of heart disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what is descriptive and predictive analysis in healthcare?</title>
      <link>/blog/hca_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 10:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/hca_intro/</guid>
      <description>Faster Diagnosis, Better Treatment: For a long time, healthcare professionals have been using data science to optimize patient outcomes. The application can include but not limited to:
 predictive analytics of frequent medical event sequence; predict healthcare event/costs/readmission rate; clustering medical records, or predicting causations between medical events; Classifying medical images/videos, etc.  Using data science allows the industry to draw actionable insights in a cost-effective way. For example, Stanford ML Group developed a model which can diagnose irregular heart rhythms from single-lead ECG signals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to add a custom domain to your hugo site?</title>
      <link>/blog/custom_domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 22:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/custom_domain/</guid>
      <description>This post introduce how to configure an apex domain to your hugo site. A lot of people prefer to have a custom domain instead &amp;ldquo;http:XXXX.github.io&amp;rdquo;. Let&amp;rsquo;s go through the steps to add your domain name to your hugo site:
Step 1: acquire a domain: I got my domain name from Google Domains. Depends on different domain names, the prices are different. For example, my domain name &amp;ldquo;JiaxinZheng.com&amp;rdquo; costs 12 bucks per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>heart disease prediction</title>
      <link>/blog/chd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 21:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/chd/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Coronary heart disease (CHD) is one of the most common types of heart disease in America. Making early prognosis can help high risk potential patients to change lifesyle and reduce the chance of getting it. The objective of the project is to determine the risk factors for predicting the probability of developing CHD.
The ‘framingham’ dataset provides information whether the participants developed Coronary Heart Disease (CHD) after ten years of the study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what is exploratory data analysis?</title>
      <link>/blog/eda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 21:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/eda/</guid>
      <description>Understanding data is one of the most important steps for anyone starting out a machine learning project. Exploratory Data Analysis is one of the ways to do that. “EDA is performed in order to define and refine the selection of feature variables that will be used for machine learning”. This post briefly talks about EDA and Bivariate Analysis.
The post will cover:
What is EDA and Bivariate Analysis
Why it is important</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>analyzing baby product purchase pattern with Excel</title>
      <link>/blog/baby_product/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 22:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/baby_product/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: Buying pattern refers to the characteristics way of customer’s buying in terms of product category, frequency, etc. It’s important for business to know customer’s buying pattern in order to make better marketing strategy to meet the need of their target consumers.
This post will analyze purchase pattern based on baby product dataset obtained from Tianchi, a sourcing company which hosts big data competitions in various industries.
Dataset Summary: This Mum_Baby dataset contains 952 baby’s information including user_id, birthday, gender which were provided by customers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>analyzing UNIQLO sales trend with Python</title>
      <link>/blog/uniqlo_sales_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 21:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/uniqlo_sales_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Sales analysis is a way to evaluate the performance of sales by analyzing sales data. In order to improve sales effectiveness and make smart decisions, it’s important to conduct sales analysis regularly. Today, I decided to share one of the sales analysis projects for UNIQLO sales data.
About UNIQLO: Uniqlo is one of the brands in Fast Retailing, a global company that operates multiple fashion brands. UNIQLO generates about 1.9 trillion Yen in annual revenue (FY 2019) from 2200 stores globally.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what is dimensionality reduction?</title>
      <link>/blog/pca/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 22:39:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/pca/</guid>
      <description>Today, I am going to talk about Feature Engineer, and more specifically, PCA which is one technique in feature extraction.
Feature Engineer is an important part of machine learning. Like a quote showed above, how your algorithm does, highly depends on your data. Feature engineer include feature selection and feature extraction. We are only going to focus on feature extraction&amp;mdash;PCA here.
What is PCA and why we are doing it?💭 PCA refers to Principal Component Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>what is k-fold cross validation?</title>
      <link>/blog/kfold/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 21:56:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/kfold/</guid>
      <description>In machine learning, we usually split the data into training and testing sets so that we can evaluate the model(s). This method, however, is not reliable because the accuracy of your model is largely depend on what you got! Accuracy obtained from one test set can be very different than another test set. This post will talk about K-fold Cross Validation.
The Validation Set Approach:❓ Usually before we train a model, we spilt the data into training and test set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there, I&amp;rsquo;m glad you found me! My name is Jessie, I recently graduated from University of St. Thomas, Data Science program. This a Hugo site hosted on Github. This website includes my thoughts/projects/learning journey.
Things I absolute love&amp;hellip; Hiking 🧗‍♀️ / Reading 📖 / Gardening 🥕 / Learning new Recipes👩🏻‍🍳
Let&amp;rsquo;s connect! 💼 LinkedIn
💻 GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/category/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/category/</guid>
      <description>Project Discover hidden diseases topics with LDA
Heart disease prediction with Machine Learning
UNIQLO Sales Analysis
Analyzing baby product purchase pattern with Excel
Concept what is k-fold cross validation?
what is dimensionality reduction?
what is exploratory data analysis?
what is association rule mining?
what is healthcare data sources?
Clinical Decision Support Systems(CDSS)
Descriptive and predictive analysis in healthcare
Hugo Web How to add a custom domain to your hugo site?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/coding_practice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/coding_practice/</guid>
      <description>Python (in progress) Easy |Two Number Sum| |Validate Subsequence| |1119| |1480| |1108| |1672| |1431| |1470| |1512| |771| |1603| |1365| |1528| |1281| |1342| |1313| |1165| |1720| |1678| |1389|
SQL (complete) Hard |1767| |1479| |1369| |1651| |1384| |1412| |1225| |569| |618| |1097| |1159| |1635| |615| |1194| |1127 |1336| |601| |571| |185| |1645| |579 |262|
Medium |1843| |1841| |1445| |1393| |1270| |1308| |1285| |1699| |1421| |1596| |1709| |1398| |1468| |1715| |534| |1364| |1077| |1440| |1355| |1613| |1532| |1112| |1204| |1321| |608| |1783| |1747| |1264| |1193| |1164| |1126| |1045| |570| |1549| |626| |1459| |1158| |1174| |612| |1501| |1341| |602| |585| |1212| |1555| 574| |580| |178| |1070| |1149| |1205| |550| |1098| |180| |1811| |578| |184| |1454| |1132| |177| |614| |1831| |1867| |1875| |1907|</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>💼 LinkedIn
💻 GitHub</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
